bearfoottheory.com 2019-12-25

# Privacy Policy / Disclosures – Bearfoot Theory

## Advertising Policy

Occasionally I partner with brands, companies, and tourism boards to share with you the latest gear or to highlight cool adventures and destinations that I think you will be interested in. And at times, I receive compensation to write about these things. This compensation can come in the form of money, free gear, tours, etc, and it helps me continue to create interesting and valuable content on this site.

But first things first. Nothing comes before YOU. My readers mean everything, and no amount of money is worth losing your trust.

When I review a product, whether I am paid or not, I provide you with my upfront and honest opinions. And that’s it. No BS, no fluff.

Also, in my blog posts, you will often find affiliate links to products on Amazon, REI and other retailers. If you purchase something using one of my links, I receive a tiny bit of compensation. This doesn’t affect the price you pay, and the modest earnings I make from affiliate links help me keep this blog running.

In 2009, the Federal Trade Commission passed new regulations that require bloggers to disclose whenever a blog post contains affiliate links or compensation was received. So please assume that any link to Amazon or another retailer on my site is an affiliate link.

If you have any questions about this policy, please feel free to [get in touch](https://bearfoottheory.com/contact/ "Contact"). I always appreciate hearing from my readers.

### Thank you for supporting me and my site!

## Privacy Policy (Updated 5/24/18)

Bearfoot Theory respects your privacy and is committed to protecting it when you visit our Web Site bearfoottheory.com. This Privacy Policy describes the types of information we may collect from you when you visit bearfoottheory.com (the “Site”), how we use the information we collect, with whom we share it, and the choices we offer you regarding our collection and use of such information.

Please read this Privacy Policy carefully. If you do not agree with the provisions of this Privacy Policy, please do not use the Site.You can access bearfoottheory.com and browse our site without disclosing any of your personal data. We do not collect personal information about individuals unless it is knowingly provided by the individual and he or she has agreed to the terms under which bearfoottheory.com will use it.

### Types of Information We Collect

We collect only the personal data that you may volunteer while using our services on your own accord  (for example, your name and email address). We may also collect non-personal information about you, meaning information that does not uniquely identify you, when you interact with the Site.

### How We Use the Information We Collect

We may use your personal information, such as your name and email address to:  
• provide you with products and services you request;  
• send you emails or other information or materials you request;  
• respond to your questions and comments and provide customer support;  
• communicate with you about our products, services, offers, and promotions;  
• operate, evaluate, and improve our business, the Site, and the products and services we offer;  
• enforce our Terms of Use and other agreements; and  
• comply with applicable legal requirements and industry standards.

If we have sent you an email, you may choose not to receive subsequent emails from us by following the unsubscribe instructions contained in each email.

### Information Collected from Cookies

We may receive information from cookies, which are pieces of data your browser stores and sends back to us when making requests. We use this information to improve your experience on our website, understand user activity, and improve the quality of our Services.

Most browsers will tell you how to stop accepting new cookies, how to be notified when you receive a new cookie, and how to disable existing cookies. Please note, however, that without cookies you may not be able to take full advantage of all of the Site’s features.

### Ads and Analytics Partners

We may partner with third-party advertisers, ad networks, and analytics providers to deliver advertising and content targeted to your interests and to better understand your use of the Site. These third parties may collect information sent by your computer, browser, or mobile device in response to a request for content, such as unique identifiers, your IP address, or other information about your computer or device. For example, we use analytics partners (such as Google Analytics) to help analyze usage and traffic for our Site. This data is anonymous and no personalized data is stored.

We may use IP addresses to compile and provide aggregate statistics about our visitors, traffic patterns, and to administer the Site. These statistics will not include any personally identifying information, rather, they track users movement and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information.

You may opt-out of the aggregation and analysis of data collected about you on our Site by our web analytics vendor by visiting [this site on Google tools](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout) and downloading and installing the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on.

### Disclosure of Information

Bearfoottheory.com will not sell, trade, or rent your personal information to others. We do not automatically log personal data nor do we link information automatically logged by other means with personal data about specific individuals.

Bearfoottheory.com may release account information when such release is reasonably necessary to comply with the law; enforce the terms of any of our user agreements; or protect the rights, property, and safety of bearfoottheory.com, the users of its site, or others.

### External Web Sites

Please note that bearfoottheory.com contains links to other websites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of these other sites. We encourage our users to be aware that when they leave our site that they read the privacy statements of each web site that might collect personally identifying information.

This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by bearfoottheory.com. If you have any questions or concerns about our privacy policy, [please contact us](https://bearfoottheory.com/contact/).

### Affiliate Disclaimer

Bearfoot Theory has financial relationships with a number of companies mentioned in this website, and bearfoottheory.com may be compensated if you make a purchase via the links on this website.

### Transactional Information

If you purchase products or services from us, we will collect certain information from you needed to fulfill your order, including your name, address, email address, and information about the product or service you are purchasing. Payments are processed by third-party payment processors (e.g., PayPal), so please refer to the applicable processor’s terms and privacy policy for more information about how payment information is processed and stored.

### Other Information

You may choose to provide other information directly to us. For example, we may collect information when you fill out a form, participate in contests, sweepstakes or promotions, apply for a job, communicate with us via third-party sites and services, request customer support or otherwise communicate with us.

### Our Commitment to Children’s Privacy

The Web Site is not directed to children. If you are under 18, you may use our services only with involvement of a parent or guardian.

### Changes

We reserve the right to update or change this Privacy Policy at any time. If we do, we will let you know by revising the date at the top of the policy. If we make a change to this policy that, in our sole discretion, is material, we will provide you with additional notice. We encourage you to review the Privacy Policy whenever you access or use our Services or otherwise interact with us to stay informed about our information practices and the ways you can help protect your privacy. If you continue to use our Services after Privacy Policy changes go into effect, you consent to the revised policy.

### Contact Us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, [please contact us](https://bearfoottheory.com/contact/).

## Disclaimer

The content of bearfoottheory.com is for general information purposes only and does not constitute professional advice. Bearfoottheory.com / Kristen bor cannot be held liable for actions arising from the use of the information on this web site.

Bearfoottheory.com tries to provide content that is true and accurate as of the date of writing; however, we give no assurance or warranty regarding the accuracy, timeliness, or applicability of any of the contents. Visitors to bearfoottheory.com should not act upon the site’s content or information without first seeking appropriate professional advice. Bearfoottheory.com expressly disclaims any and all warranties, expressed or implied, to the extent permitted by law, including but not limited to warranties of satisfactory advice. Bearfoottheory.com excludes liability for any claims, losses, demands, or damages of any kind whatsoever with regard to any information, content, or services provided at our website, including but not limited to direct, indirect, incidental, or consequential loss or damages, compensatory damages, loss of profits, or data, or otherwise.

Reference within this site to any specific commercial or non-commercial product, process, or service by trade name, trademark, manufacturer or otherwise does not constitute or imply an endorsement, recommendation, or favoring by bearfoottheory.com. The content published on bearfoottheory.com expresses the opinions and views of the authors. References to any products in articles are specific suggestions only and do not necessarily constitute or imply an endorsement.

Links to external or third party websites, are provided solely for visitors’ convenience. Links taken to other sites are done so at your own risk and bearfoottheory.com accepts no liability for any linked sites or their content. When you access an external website, keep in mind that bearfoottheory.com has no control over its content. Any link from bearfoottheory.com to an external website does not imply or mean that bearfoottheory.com endorses or accepts any responsibility for the content or the use of such website. Bearfoottheory.com does not give any representation regarding the quality, safety, suitability, or reliability of any external websites or any of the content or materials contained in them. It is important for users to take necessary precautions, especially to ensure appropriate safety from viruses, other cybersecurity risks.
